Daniel Lagos

910.916.7201 | Lagos.D@gmail.com | San Diego, CA

LinkedIn Profile | GitHub Account | Portfolio

Machine Learning Engineer

Machine Learning Engineer backed by 10 years of experience as an officer in the US Army and as an operations manager. Seeking a full-time position where I can apply my creativity and analytical, software engineering, and machine learning skills to help people and organizations solve complex problems and seize opportunities.

Skills

- Python, Jupyter, Pandas, Numpy, Matlib, Scikit-Learn, GitHub
- SAS Enterprise Guide, SAS Data Miner
- JavaScript, Vue, React, Node, Express, SQL
- Deep learning architectures: CNNs, RNNs, Transformers
- Statistical Model Building & ML Optimization

- Data Analysis, Data Mining & Data Auditing
- Feature Engineering and Data Visualization
- Continuous and Categorical Data Methods
- Data Analysis Interpretation & Application
- Large Data Files & Dataset Management
- Agile Software Development

Education

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY, 2022 – 2023, GPA: 4.0

Master of Science, Data Science, Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning - Graduation Date: 04/2023

UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX, 2008 – 2010, GPA: 4.0

Master of Business Administration, Finance (32/36 units)

LA SIERRA UNIVERSITY, 2001 – 2003

Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration, eCommerce

Experience

National University, Master's Candidate in Data Science

Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning

2022 - 2023

- Complete advanced data science coursework while maintaining a 4.0 grade point average.
- Develop advanced skills in mathematical and statistical models (e.g., discrete event simulation, factor analysis, genetic algorithms, hidden Markov models, probability, regression, PCA, time-series analysis.)

Case Studies:

- <u>Principal Component Analysis</u>. Based study on 2009 California Health Interview Survey to find 3 factors (out
 of 536 variables) to measure correlation between patients taking medication to mitigate heart disease,
 receiving medical treatment for heart disease, and their mental state.
- <u>Suicide and Gender</u>. Employed multivariable logistic regression to find the association between suicide attempts and gender among high school student in the United States.
- Ordinal Logistic Regression. Measured association between poverty levels and depression after adjusting for physical activity among adults in the state of California.
- Technology: Python, SAS Enterprise Guide, SAS Data Miner, Jupyter, Pandas, Numpy, Matlib, Scikit Learn.

MortgageOne, Junior Processor

2020 - 2022

- Personally processed loans for branch manager and 5 other loan officers.
- Prioritized and managed a pipeline of 17 to 25 loans per month while acting as a liaison between loan officer, title, and underwriting to ensure closing within 30 to 35 days in 97% of files.

- Managed and processes 28 to 32 invoices per day valued in total of \$1,000 to \$5,000/day.
- Developed procedures saving the department approximately \$3,000 per year in labor expenses.

Discrete Chill, Junior Web Developer

2018 - 2019

- Led reformatting initiative to convert web application from jQuery, HTML, CSS to Vue.JS components.
- Built scalable API using TypeScript and GraphQL to fetch product records to assist users in product selection based on customers' requirements/symptoms.
- Presented Tech Talk explaining the three forms of artificial intelligence/machine learning: supervised learning, unsupervised learning, and reinforced learning.
- Technology: JavaScript, React, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, React Materialize, GitHub, MySQL Workbench, AWS Amplify, AWS Cognito, AWS DynamoDB, AWS App Sync.

Movement Mortgage, Branch Manager

2016 - 2018

- Managed 17 loan officers, 4 loan officer assistants, and 2 processors for a high-volume mortgage broker producing on average \$38MM in mortgage loans per month.
- Developed and implemented sales training programs and best practices improving team sales skills, thereby increasing monthly sales volume by 13%.
- Implemented data-driven solutions identifying waste in over-processing and motion and to improve speed of mortgage processing transactions by 17%.
- Developed referral partner relationships with 12 realtors, and 3 CPA's, to augment purchase volume.

Self-Employed, Mortgage Loan Officer

2010 – 2016

- Self-sourced mortgage loan officer responsible for developing consumer direct marketing campaigns for first-time home buyers and cash-out refinance clients.
- Funded an average of 7 loans per month totaling approximately \$2.8MM in funded loans.

US Army, Operations Officer (Operations Officer) - Captain

2006 - 2008

- Led and supervised 4 first line supervisors and 78 service-members responsible for Medical, Testing, and Operations Departments for US Military's largest Recruit Entrance Processing Station.
- Oversaw the processing, contracting, physical examination, and shipping of over 12,000 applicants per year into their respective branches of military service.
- Negotiated all non-traditional business relationships within Los Angeles area including physician networks and hospitality operations.
- Mapped, documented, and redesigned LA MEPS business processes increasing capacity by 63%.

US Army, IT Business Analyst (S6) - Captain

2006

- Led IT Department consisting of 5 soldiers responsible for all communications and IT assets for a newly commissioned 600-man Aviation Support Battalion.
- Field tested and deployed Battalion Communication assets including newly fielded Joint Network Node system, Secure Internet Protocol, Non-Secure Internet Protocol, Command Post Network system, Fusion Net, and ASIP radio network.
- Streamlined operations by creating standardized practices for IT processes, improving efficiency by 27%.
- Developed IT training program for 600 soldiers in preparation for Operation Enduring Freedom V (deployment to Afghanistan).

US Army, General Manager (Platoon Leader) - 1st Lieutenant

2004 - 2006

- Tactical communications leader providing worldwide support to XVIII Airborne Corps Headquarters.
- Led and supervised 4 subordinate first line supervisors, and a total of 76 Soldiers, and was responsible for 15 tactical vehicles, 5 communications assemblages, and other auxiliary equipment valued over \$8MM.
- Set up NIPR and SIPR net, deployed VOIP network, and maintained LAN in Iraq LSA Anaconda.
- Streamlined business processes to achieve operational readiness of 97%, 7% above battalion standard.

Daniel Lagos Resume, pg. 2 | 910.916.7201 | Lagos.D@gmail.com | San Diego, CA